## ANANTH PAI

ananthtpai@gmail.com | +919035208166 | linkedin.com/in/ananth-pai/ | ananthpai.in

#### **SUMMARY**

8+ years of experience working on web applications with experience in both frontend and backend with strong Javascript fundamentals. A problem solver at heart. I would like to think of myself as someone who strives to improve oneself daily and achieve excellence in whatever I take up.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Frontend Lead, AppsForBharat

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

As a Frontend lead my responsibilities include architecting and leading all the frontend projects happening at the company. I am also tasked with helping my team continuously improve and become better developers. Other than my role as a lead I also built the following

- Social Chat: This project was challenging since it meant adding React Native code to our existing Android Application which lead to the creation of a Hybrid App. Used Expo and Storybook to quickly integrate all the UI components and speed up the development process. You can download the Android App here.
- Built the Internal CMS for our business and content teams.
- Setup Prettier, ESLint, Husky, and lint staged that helped us maintain a consistent codebase.

# Frontend Engineer/Founding Member (Part Time), ResumePuppy.com

Jan 2020 - Present

- My core responsibilities include the feasibility of Frontend-related features and implementation using **React**.
- Helped build the product from the ground up from the initial concept to the full-fledged app.
- Responsible for building our microservice architecture using **Docker** for easy deployments.
- Setup the Nginx configs for easy routing and reverse proxying between our multiple services.
- Worked on integrating monetization workflows into the application.
- Currently working on adding a public share feature.

## Software Engineer, Peritus AI

Aug 2018 - Nov 2021

- Built the frontend of our **Chrome Extension** (i.e Peritus Assistant) that helps SME's resolve support tickets using our proprietary recommendations engine. You can find the Peritus Assistant on the Chrome Web Store here.
- Built the microservice that handles login and authentication using **SpringBoot** + **Kotlin**, this is now being used extensively in multiple applications across our organization to authenticate the user.
- Built the web application using **React** + **Webpack**, along with using styled-components to style the webpages. Used StorybookJS to help with component documentation.
- Built a versatile system using **Webpack** and **Docker** to house common code in the same repo but be able to build multiple products
- ullet Built multiple apps for different platforms such as ServiceNow, Salesforce, and JIRA using **React**
- Setup a versatile dev environment using docker so that there is no hindrance for anyone wanting to set up the frontend for development
- Architected the frontend **Typescript** instead of Javascript. This allowed us to develop quicker as types for different libraries were readily available as well as helped us considerably clean up our codebase and allow for stricter coding guidelines

### Full Stack Engineer, Absolute Sports Pvt Ltd

Jul 2016 - May 2018

- Code clean-up and architecture overhaul of our main application, as well as the removal of our legacy WordPress system.
- Planning, and Implementation of our Revenue Share module.
- Integration of data from various third-party vendors, so as to be used to display content on our main application.

### Software Engineer, Robosoft Technologies Pvt Ltd

Aug 2013 - Jul 2016

- Worked on multiple service projects where I build CMSes and APIs to be used in Android and iOS applications
- Worked on cocos2d-x, building world-class games for International clients.

### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication

Jun 2009 - May 2013

Visvesvaraya Technological University

GPA: 9.36

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Webpack, NodeJS, Nginx, Docker, StorybookJS, npm, Redux, Mobx, NextJS, React Native

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, redis